Esteban Mendez



edmendezn@gmail.com



(201) 360 - 1905 Mobile



linkedin.com/in/esteban-mendez-63515290



https://esmendez90.github.io/esmendez portfolio/

Summary

I am very hardworking, and willing to learn. I do not mind going the extra mile. A strong work ethic is an essential aspect in my work history as well. -Strong verbal communication skills with patients or clients of all levels (Physicians & Staff). Worked in Healthcare for over several years.

Experience



NYP Holter Analyst

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital

May 2017 - Present (4 years +)

- Scan and analyze data from cardiac-function monitoring devices worn by patients for use in diagnosis of cardiovascular disorders.
- Record findings on report form and forwards tapes, form, patient diary, and printouts of heart patterns to interpreting physician.

Telemetry Technician

Jersey City Medical Center

Feb 2009 - May 2017 (8 years 4 months)

- · Provide advanced ECG while concentrating on monitoring patient status through assessment of ECG strips and arrhythmia interpretation.
- Identify and respond to potentially life-threatening cardiac rhythm changes.

Education



Rutgers University

Certificate, Web Development

Dec 2020 - May 2021

Student-developer with a passion for front-end coding and knowledge of back-end coding.

American Training School

Certificate, Medical/Clinical Assistant

Jul 2008 - Apr 2009

Nationally certified in electrocardiogram, phlebotomy, and medical assistant.

Skills

Front-end Coding • back-end Coding • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Node.js • Patient Safety • Medical Terminology • Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR) • Spanish